## Victoria Perkins

318-237-9651 | vep002@gmail.com Github | Medium | LinkedIn

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Policy analyst turned welder turned full stack developer with hands-on experience in JavaScript, React, and Ruby on Rails. My unconventional background encapsulates my pursuit of constant learning as well as my skills in problem solving, project management, and design thinking.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, React, Active Record, SQL, Ruby, Nokogiri, RoR, Java, Spring, Spring Boot.

#### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

## The Sewcialist Agenda GitHub | Demo

A project management and inspiration app for fiber artists.

- Utilized JWT and localStorage to authenticate and authorize client-side user actions.
- Built schema using the MVC pattern and RESTful conventions with Ruby on Rails and a Postgres database.
- Implemented React routes to enable seamless UX in the single-page application.
- Developed a unique UI using Material UI and custom CSS.

# My Garden Center GitHub | Demo

A houseplant care and tracking app.

- Developed a backend JSON server with Active Record, Sinatra, and a SQLite database.
- Constructed a frontend using JavaScript, React, and custom CSS elements.

## Rotten Cabbages GitHub | Demo

A movie review app.

Enabled asynchronous communication with the MovieDB and Youtube APIs in order to perform CRUD operations based on client-side user input.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### LeJeune Steel Company

Minneapolis, MN

Fitter Welder

**Child Trends** 

09/2020 - 03/2021

- Performed pre-inspection weld testing using industry standard gauges to preemptively catch any errors or defects.
- Communicated project needs and specifications across multiple shop departments to ensure efficient turn-around.

Drill Pipe, Inc. Winstead, MN Welder 05/2020 - 08/2020

Interpreted schematics in order to machine pipe fittings to within 0.10 inch tolerance.

Contributed to increased quality and production speed.

Research Analyst - Senior Research Analyst

Minneapolis, MN 08/2016 - 01/2020

- Coordinated the publication of a national report, interactive maps, and web profiles of all 50 states by communicating research findings and technical specifications between the research team and a web developer.
- Managed the process for creating four separate budget forecasts for a Federal funding proposal totaling over \$3M.

### **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** Full Stack Web Development, Immersive Software Engineering program Manhattan, NY

04/2021 - 08/2021

University of Minnesota, Humphrey School of Public Affairs

Master of Public Policy

Minneapolis, MN 05/2016

**Louisiana Tech University** 

BA in English

Ruston, LA 05/2021